MARCO ANTONIO DE JESUS CIRIACO

477 321 28 20 | marco_dejesus@live.com

PROFILE

5 years of experience as Software Tester, I've implemented and trained QA Team (India and Mexico) into a UI Automation Testing Framework in Ruby language with the Page Object Model. The Framework is based on Cucumber. I work with Postman scripts for API call responses validation. I'm the Scrum Master of my Team and I remove blockers that go beyond the team scope. I conduct and participate in different ceremonies as Scrum of Scrum meetings, Sprint Planning sessions, Daily Stand-up meeting, Retrospective meetings and others. I Led a Testing Team during many different Test Cycles with up to 15 Team members. I got experience on different Manual Testing Types (Functional and Non-Functional) such as: Smoke, Regression, Usability, Accessibility and Cross Browser Testing in different Testing Levels (Integration, System and Acceptance Testing). I have experience on Defect Management, Defect Lifecycle, Software Development Lifecycle and Software Testing Lifecycle.

2 years of experience as Java Developer in Core Java for Web Applications (JSP) and web technologies such as JSON, JQuery, Ajax, xHTML and CSS with Tomcat Server and Xampp stack for PHP development; I worked with Three Layer Applications Model (Data Layer, Business Layer and Presentation Layer) with JPA; I got experience on Triggers, Stored Procedures and Functions as well as Nested Queries in RDBMS.

EDUCATION

Universidad de la Salle Bajio Campus Campestre. Leon, Guan	ajuato.
--	---------

Master Degree in Administrative Engineering and Quality May 2015

Universidad Tecnologica de Leon. Leon, Guanajuato.

Bachelor's Degree on Information Technologies Engineer April 2012

Universidad Tecnologica de Leon. Leon, Guanajuato.

Technical Degree on Computer Systems April 2010

Universidad de la Salle Bajio Campus Campestre Leon, Guanajuato.

Diploma in Software Development (.NET Framework 3.5)

June 2010

CERTIFICATIONS

Scaled Agile, Inc.

Certified SAFe® 4 Agilist July 2018

ISTQB - International Software Testing Qualifications Board

ISTQB® Certified Tester, Foundation Level – Licence 16-CTFL-97055-03 Aug 2016

SCRUMStudy

Scrum Master Certified (SMC) – Licence 97915 April 2016

Sofftek

Certified Six Sigma – Yellow Belt Sept 2016

Technical Skills

Quality Tools

Waste Elimination, Muda, 7/8 wastes, Value Stream Mapping, Cycle Time Reduction, Continuous Flow, Kanban, 5S, Standard Work, Poka yoke, Kaizen, TPM, Visual Control, Statistical Quality Control.

Testing Tools

Selenium Web Driver, Test Manager, Team Foundation Server, Rational Clear Quest, Rational Requisite Pro, Rational Quality Manager, Total Validator Tool, Juicy Studio, Chrome Vox Screen Reader, SharePoint 2010, Excel Macros Development, SOAP UI, Postman.

Application Servers, IDEs, Build and integration tools

IntellijIDE, VSCode, Visual Studio 2017, Eclipse, Git, NetBeans, MS SQL Management Studio, MySQL Workbench, Jenkins, Docker.

OS and DB Manager System

Apache Server, Tomcat, Xampp, Unix-like systems (Ubuntu, iMac), MySQL, MS SQL Server 2005

Software Methodologies and others

SAFe, Scrum, V-Model, JDBC, XML, Rspec, Splunk

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Herbalife

QA Analyst September 2016 – Current

I'm responsible to do the analysis of the Business requirements and to create SQL stored procedures scenarios for Business Logic validation as well as Automated Test Scripts for UI and API calls. UI scripts are written on Cucumber to have Executable Specifications. API scripts are written on Postman and executed through Newman. SQL Store procedures are manually validated but we're getting to use TSQLT for unit testing. From QA perspective we use Docker to pull images and run scripts in local environment. Also, as the Scrum Master, I'm responsible to track the Team effort and update the TFS Kanban board, remove impediments and mitigate risks. All this following the guidelines of the Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) during a two weeks sprint time frame.

Softtek

Senior QA Analyst

I was in charge of developing Manual and Automated Test Scripts. Automated Scripts were written in C# and executed through Visual Studio. TFS was used for the Code Integration. I followed the Scrum methodology and closed the gap between Business team and Development team; I helped the team to get used to work with Scrum.

June 2015 - September 2016

May 2011 - May 2012

UST Global

Tester November 2012 – June 2015

I worked with V-Model and I led a 15 people Testing Team. As part of my daily activities, I used to provide the Testing Report to the Customer and doing the analysis of Defect reports. I played the role as Defect Manager and coordinated and followed up all high priority Bugs with the respective teams. I also led 2 sub-teams, one for Accessibility Testing in order to comply with 508 standards and another for Cross-Browser Testing.

create the required tables and its relationship. Do the breakdown of Java classes and do the implementation of them with JPA and finally create the Front end

Univesidad Tecnologica de Leon

Java Developer

Even though the main activities were for Software Development in Java programming language, I needed to Gather the Requirements and talk directly with end users. Do the analysis on how the database tables should relate and

with Jquery Themes.

Smar Yeo Consultores TI (Software Development Consulting)

PHP Developer

My activities were to create Websites in Joomla and, if required by the customer, create modules in PHP like send email, contact, etc.

Teletech

Customer Service Representative

Customer service in English/Spanish for Sprint-Nextel campaign Tech Support and Radio Solutions Billing Service Support

January 2009 - March 2009

March 2010 - November 2010

LANGUAGES

Spanish – Native

English - Speak, Read, and Write

ASPIRATIONS AND EXPECTATIONS

Following my Career Path will brand me as a very Strong Associate for a company in Quality and Processes Improvement, becoming an essential advisor, leading the company to grow. I'm dreaming of with creating my own company.

I'm expecting to work with people from different countries in order to learn from them new ways of work, culture and experiences.